Register of the Raymond Albert Wheeler papers, 1898-1977
Hoover Institution Archives
- Mekong River Basin File, 1957-1974 (Boxes 27-33)
  - Newsletters
    - 1961 (Box-folder 31: 4)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 31: 5)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Notes
    - Undated (Box-folder 31: 7-8)
    - 1964-1971 (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Press releases (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 31: 11-13)
  - Projects of the Mekong River Basin
    - Undated (Box-folder 31: 14)
    - 1963-1968 (Box-folder 31: 15)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 31: 16)
  - Proposal (Box-folder 31: 17)
  - Reports
    - Undated (Box-folder 31: 18)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 32: 1)
    - 1968-1970 (Box-folder 32: 2-4)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 32: 5)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Schedule (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - Statements
    - Undated (Box-folder 32: 8)
    - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 32: 9-10)
    - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 32: 11-12)
    - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 32: 13-14)
  - Telegrams
    - Undated (Box-folder 32: 15)
    - 1957-1958 (Box-folder 32: 16-17)
    - 1963-1969 (Box-folder 32: 18-24)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 32: 25)
  - Writings on Mekong River Project by others, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 33: 1-6)
    Including Kanwar Sain, C. Hart Schaaf, and Virginia Wheeler.
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 33: 7)
- World Bank File, 1948-1973 (Boxes 34-36)
  Charts, clippings, comments, correspondence, cost, interview, itinerary, map, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, pamphlets, press releases, printed matter, remarks, reports, schedule, statements, and telegrams relating to the World Bank in general and to Raymond Wheeler's work in Jordan and in India in the settlement of the dispute between India and Pakistan over the use of the Indus River waters as an official of the World Bank, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Also includes records relating to his retirement from the World Bank.
  - General (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Congo file, report, 1962 (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - Correspondence
    - 1948-1956 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - 1959-1963 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    - 1964-1966 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 34: 6-7)
    - 1969-1971 (Box-folder 34: 8-9)
  - Indus River Project file
    - General (Box-folder 34: 10)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 34: 11)
    - Comments (Box-folder 34: 12)
    - Correspondence
      - 1951-1959 (Box-folder 34: 13)
      - 1960-1961 (Box-folder 34: 14)
      - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 34: 15)
      - 1964-1967 (Box-folder 34: 16-19)
      - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 34: 20)
      - 1971-1973 (Box-folder 34: 21)
    - Cost assessment (Box-folder 34: 22)
    - Dam sites list (Box-folder 34: 23)
    - Development fund and loan agreements (Box-folder 34: 24-25)
    - Drawings and tables (Box-folder 34: 26)
    - Indus Valley negotiations and settlement plan (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - Interviews (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - Irrigation, link canals, and remodelling plan (Box-folder 35: 3-4)
    - Itinerary (Box-folder 35: 5)
    - Maps (Box-folder 35: 6)
    - Memoranda
      - 1952 (Box-folder 35: 7)
      - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 35: 8)
      - 1961-1963 (Box-folder 35: 9)
    - Minutes of meetings (Box-folder 35: 10)
    - Notes (Box-folder 35: 11)
    - Pamphlets (Box-folder 35: 12)
    - Personnel records (Box-folder 35: 13)
    - Press releases (Box-folder 35: 14)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 35: 15-16)
    - Remarks (Box-folder 35: 17)
    - Reports
      - Undated (Box-folder 35: 18)
      - 1954 May (Box-folder 35: 19)
      - 1957 October (Box-folder 35: 20)
      - 1959 May, December (Box-folder 35: 21-22)
      - 1960 April (Box-folder 35: 23)
      - 1962 July-December (Box-folder 35: 24)
      - 1963 October (Box-folder 35: 25)
    - Schedules (Box-folder 35: 26)
    - Statements (Box-folder 35: 27)
    - Writings by others, 1961 (Box-folder 36: 1)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - Interview as part of Oral History Project with Columbia University, 1969 (Box-folder 36: 3)
  - Jordan file
    - General (Box-folder 36: 4)
    - Agreements between Jordan and Syria (Box-folder 36: 5)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 36: 6)
    - Correspondence
      - 1962 (Box-folder 36: 7)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 36: 8)
    - Cost assessment (Box-folder 36: 9)
    - Maps (Box-folder 36: 10)
    - Memoranda, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 36: 11-12)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1962 (Box-folder 36: 13)
    - Notes (Box-folder 36: 14)
    - Plan of sharing the waters (Box-folder 36: 15)
    - Remarks (Box-folder 36: 16-17)
    - Reports
      - Undated (Box-folder 36: 18)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 36: 19)
      - 1961-1962 (Box-folder 36: 20-21)
    - Writings by others, 1955 (Box-folder 36: 22)
  - Memoranda
    - 1953-1959 (Box-folder 36: 23)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 36: 24)
    - 1972 (Box-folder 36: 25)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1958 (Box-folder 36: 26)
  - Newsletters (Box-folder 36: 27)
  - Notes (Box-folder 36: 28)
  - Organizational chart (Box-folder 36: 29)
  - Pamphlets (Box-folder 36: 30)
  - Panama file
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 36: 31)
    - Memoranda, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 36: 32)
  - Personnel records (Box-folder 36: 33)
    Includes Raymond Wheeler's letter of appointment as Engineering Consultant.
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 36: 34)
  - Projects description (Box-folder 36: 35)
  - Retirement records
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Box-folder 36: 36)
      - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 36: 37-38)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 36: 39)
  - Service records (Box-folder 36: 40)
  - Telegrams (Box-folder 36: 41)
  - Writings by others, 1969 (Box-folder 36: 42)
- United Nations File, 1953-1969 (Boxes 37-39)
  Clippings, communications, communique, correspondence, drawings, interview, itinerary, maps, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, organizational chart, pamphlets, press release, printed matter, remarks, reports, schedule, telegrams, and miscellany relating to Raymond Wheeler's work on behalf of the United Nations on the public works construction program and transport system in Congo and his service as head of the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Also includes the participation of Virginia Wheeler as a representative of the Mekong Committee at the ad hoc Panel of Experts on Legal and Institutional Implications of International Water Resources Development in New York and memoranda sent by Virginia Wheeler as a financial adviser to the United Nations relating to the Congo project. Includes materials in French. See also: World Bank File.
  - Agreements (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Congo file
    - General (Box-folder 37: 2)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 37: 3)
    - Communication facilities (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - Communique (Box-folder 37: 5)
    - Contracts (Box-folder 37: 6)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Box-folder 37: 7)
      - 1960 July-November (Box-folder 37: 8-11)
      - 1963 January-September (Box-folder 37: 12-13)
      - 1964 January-March (Box-folder 37: 14)
    - Cost assessment (Box-folder 37: 15)
    - Drawings (Box-folder 37: 16)
    - Interviews (Box-folder 37: 17)
    - Itinerary (Box-folder 37: 18)
    - Maps (Box-folder 37: 19)
    - Memoranda
      - Undated (Box-folder 37: 20)
      - 1960 July-October (Box-folder 37: 21-24)
    - Messages (Box-folder 37: 25)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1960 July-October (Box-folder 37: 26-29)
    - Notes (Box-folder 37: 30)
    - Organizational chart (Box-folder 37: 31)
    - Pamphlets (Box-folder 37: 32)
    - Personnel records (Box-folder 37: 33)
    - Press releases (Box-folder 37: 34)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 37: 35)
    - Project description (Box-folder 37: 36)
    - Radio broadcast (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - Reports
      - Undated (Box-folder 38: 2)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 38: 3)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 38: 4)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - Schedule (Box-folder 38: 6)
    - Security Council resolutions (Box-folder 38: 7)
    - Telegrams
      - Undated (Box-folder 38: 8)
      - 1960 July-October (Box-folder 38: 9-12)
      - 1963 January-February (Box-folder 38: 13-14)
    - Writings by others, undated (Box-folder 38: 15)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 38: 16)
  - Correspondence
    - 1960 (Box-folder 38: 17)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 38: 18)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 38: 19)
  - Palestine file
    - Clippings (Box-folder 38: 20)
    - Correspondence, 1953 August-December (Box-folder 38: 21)
    - Editorials commending Raymond Wheeler's appointment (Box-folder 38: 22)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 38: 23)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 38: 24)
  - Remarks (Box-folder 38: 25)
  - Reports (Box-folder 38: 26)
  - United Nations Seminar on Management of International Water Resources file
    - General (Box-folder 38: 27)
    - Correspondence
      - 1969-1970 (Box-folder 38: 28-29)
      - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 38: 30-31)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 38: 32)
    - Proposal (Box-folder 38: 33)
    - Reports
      - Undated (Box-folder 38: 34)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 38: 35)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 38: 36)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Writings by others, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 39: 2)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 39: 3)
- Columbia River Project File, 1963-1972 (Boxes 39-42)
  Clippings, correspondence, drawings, graphs, itinerary, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, printed matter, reports, schedule, telegrams, and miscellany relating to Raymond Wheeler's service on a review panel organized by the British Columbia Hydro and Power Authority for study of the plans of the Columbia River projects, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Box-folder 39: 6)
    - 1964
      - February-March (Box-folder 39: 7-8)
      - May-December (Box-folder 39: 9-16)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 39: 17-28)
    - 1966 January-November (Box-folder 39: 29-39)
    - 1967
      - January-April (Box-folder 39: 40-43)
      - May-September (Box-folder 40: 1-5)
      - December (Box-folder 40: 6)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 40: 7-18)
    - 1969
      - January-August (Box-folder 40: 19-26)
      - October-December (Box-folder 40: 27-29)
    - 1970
      - January-May (Box-folder 40: 30-34)
      - July-September (Box-folder 40: 35-37)
      - November-December (Box-folder 40: 38-39)
    - 1971
      - January-August (Box-folder 40: 40-47)
      - October (Box-folder 40: 48)
    - 1972
      - April (Box-folder 41: 1)
      - July (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Cost (Box-folder 41: 3)
  - Drawings (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - Field logs (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - Graphs (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - Itinerary (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - Memoranda
    - 1964 July-August (Box-folder 41: 8-9)
    - 1966 December (Box-folder 41: 10)
    - 1968 October (Box-folder 41: 11)
    - 1969
      - February (Box-folder 41: 12)
      - April (Box-folder 41: 13)
      - October (Box-folder 41: 14)
  - Minutes of meetings
    - Undated (Box-folder 41: 15)
    - 1963 May (Box-folder 41: 16)
    - 1964
      - July-September (Box-folder 41: 17)
      - November (Box-folder 41: 18)
    - 1965
      - January (Box-folder 41: 19)
      - December (Box-folder 41: 20)
    - 1966 May (Box-folder 41: 21)
    - 1967
      - February (Box-folder 41: 22)
      - July-August (Box-folder 41: 23-24)
    - 1968
      - February (Box-folder 41: 25)
      - May (Box-folder 41: 26)
      - July (Box-folder 41: 27)
      - December (Box-folder 41: 28)
  - Notes (Box-folder 41: 29)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 41: 30)
  - Reports
    - Undated (Box-folder 41: 31)
    - 1968-1971 (Box-folder 41: 32-35)
  - Schedule (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Telegrams
    - Undated (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - Writings by others, 1971 (Box-folder 42: 6)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 42: 7)
- Subject File, 1954-1985 (Boxes 42-45)
  Agreement, brochures, bulletins, charts, clippings, comments, correspondence, maps, minutes of meetings, memoranda, newsletters, notes, pamphlets, printed matter, remarks, reports, telegram, and miscellany, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Afghanistan (Box-folder 42: 8-9)
  - Africa (Box-folder 42: 10-13)
  - American Institute of Consulting Engineers (Box-folder 42: 14-21)
  - Burma (Box-folder 42: 22-28)
  - China (Box-folder 42: 29)
  - Engineering research (Box-folder 42: 30-35)
  - Environment (Box-folder 42: 36)
  - Greece (Box-folder 42: 37)
  - India (Box-folder 42: 38-42)
  - Japan (Box-folder 42: 43)
  - Latin America (Box-folder 42: 44-46)
  - Middle East (Box-folder 42: 47-50)
  - Middle East (Box-folder 43: 1-24)
  - Pakistan (Box-folder 43: 25-29)
  - Philippines (Box-folder 43: 30)
  - Russia (Box-folder 43: 31)
  - Society of American Military Engineers (SAME) (Box-folder 44: 1-18)
  - The Beavers (Box-folder 44: 19-21)
    A society of the heavy construction industry of the West Coast of the United States.
  - The Moles (Box-folder 44: 22-25)
    A society of the heavy construction industry of the East Coast of the United States.
  - Tuchman, Barbara (Box-folder 44: 26-32)
  - United Kingdom (Box-folder 44: 33-34)
  - Urban development (Box-folder 44: 35-39)
  - Vanderbilt University (Box-folder 45: 1-19)
  - Virginia (Box-folder 45: 20)
  - Water resources (Box-folder 45: 21-31)
  - Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) (Box-folder 45: 32-39)
- Oversize Material, 1917-1967 (Boxes 46-51)
  Certificates and scrapbooks relating to Raymond Wheeler's service in the United States Army, the surrender of Singapore, and sketch, general plan, and reproductions of photographs of the Suez Canal. Also included is a certificate of Raymond Wheeler's membership in the Order of Bearers of the Master Key to the Panama Canal.
  - Certificates, 1917-1959 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Certificates for temporary appointments as Major and Lieutenant Colonel in the Corps of Engineers, United States Army, 1917-1918
    - Certificate for membership in The Esteemed Order of Bearers of the Master Key to the Panama Canal, 1959
  - Printed matter, Phoenix, 1945 February 24 (Box-folder 46: 2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1941-1946
    - Commanding General, India Burma Theatre, 1942-1945 (Boxes 47-48)
    - Deputy Supreme Allied Commander, India Burma Theater, 1942-1945 (Boxes 49-50)
    - Singapore surrender, 1945 September 10 (Box 51)
    - United States Army, 1941 (Box-folder 46: 3-4)
      Includes loose photographs.
  - Suez Canal
    - Diagrammatic sketch indicating obstructions in Suez Canal, 1956 December 31 (Box-folder 46: 5)
    - General plan of the Suez Canal and reproductions of photographs of the Suez Canal, 1957, undated (Box-folder 46: 6)
- Memorabilia, 1911, 1959, undated (Box-folder 46: 7)
  Includes armband representing Wheeler's year of graduation from West Point, pennant, button from Rotary International, and the Master Key to the Panama Canal.
  - Armband, undated
  - Button, Rotary International, undated
  - Pennant, 1911
  - Master Key to the Panama Canal, 1959
- Motion Picture Film Reels, 1956-1957 (Film shelf)
  5 films relating to Wheeler's review of Engineer Center troops, his trip to Brazil, his visit to Florida with his family, a construction project in Peoria, Illinois, and his work in Suez Canal operations.
  - "General Wheeler Reviews Engineer Center Troops - Army Trains Engineers for the Air Forces," 16mm, color reversal Kodachrome, silent, undated (Reel 1)
  - "Modern Brazil, A Great Story of Service and Progress," 16mm, sound, undated (Reel 2)
  - "Olive, Peggy in Florida," 16mm, color, silent, undated (Reel 3)
  - Operation Earthmover for Exposition Gardens, under personal direction of Lt. General Raymond A. Wheeler, Chief Engineer, United States Army, Peoria, Illinois, 16mm, color, 1948 April 24-25 (Reel 4)
  - Suez Canal Clearance - United Nations Review, commentator Charles Lynch, produced by United Nations Television for Canadian Broadcasting Television, 16mm, black and white, sound, undated (Reel 5)
- Sound Recordings, 1965-1970 (Tape cabinet)
  6 sound tape reels relating to reunions of the Fourth Engineers, United States Army, Oakland, California, including 1 tape of an interview and meeting with Raymond and Virginia Wheeler at the San Francisco airport.
  - Interview and meeting with Raymond and Virginia Wheeler at the San Francisco airport, California, 1965 (Tape 1)
  - Fourth Engineers' Association of California reunion, Villa Peluso, Oakland, California, 1966 May 14 (Tape 2)
  - Tape taken from one recorded on at Fourth Engineers' Reunion, Oakland, California, 1967 June 3 (Tape 3)
  - Ellis to Wheelers, 1968 August 2 (Tape 4)
  - Fourth Engineers' reunion, 1969 July 16-18 (Tape 5)
  - Fourth Engineers' reunion, Oakland, California, 1970 July 23-24 (Tape 6)
- Photographs, 1899-1967 (Photo file, Album shelf)
  730 prints and 6 albums depicting Raymond Wheeler with his family and others, including Paul Bourtieres, Dag Hammarskjold, Kamel Hamza, Lord Mountbatten, Gamal Abdul Nasser, P. S. Narayan Prasad, Kanwar Sain, and Albert Schaff, and his years of association with the United States Army, the building of the Ledo Road, his work at the Mekong River Basin and in the clearance of the Suez Canal, and his visit to the Congo, India, and Pakistan.
  - 37 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler and his family, including 5 prints of Virginia Wheeler; 1 print of Olive Wheeler; 2 prints of the Wheeler house in Honolulu; 2 prints of sketches of Raymond Wheeler; and 1 print of the Avery Company building where Raymond Wheeler worked for four years between graduation from high school and appointment to West Point, 1899-1963 (Envelope A)
  - 51 prints of Raymond Wheeler in army uniform with others, including 1 print of Company of Engineers; 1 print of flags presented by or for Raymond Wheeler and others; and 2 prints of his official oil printing as Chief of Engineers, undated (Envelope B-C)
  - 3 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler and others during their visit to the Rock Island Engineer District, Rock Island, Illinois; 1 print of clock tower building; and 1 print of Raymond Wheeler at his desk in the Engineers office, 1934-1936 (Envelope D)
  - 14 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler and others; 1 print of Raymond Wheeler as Deputy Supreme Allied Commander of Southeast Asia Command; 1 print of Camp Crowder, Missouri; and 1 print of soldiers in special drill demonstration for members of Congress at Fort Belvoir, Virginia, 1941-1944 (Envelope E)
  - 6 prints depicting the building of the Ledo Road, starting from Ledo in Assam, India, going southward eventually to join with the old Burma Road, 1944 (Envelope F)
  - 31 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler and others, including 1 print of Lt. General Wheeler in his Deputy Supreme Allied Commander's office; 1 print depicting him inspecting forward installations in Burma and the fronts; 1 print of his daughter, Margaret Wheeler; and 4 prints of Raymond Wheeler with Lord Mountbatten, 1945-1946 (Envelope G)
  - 27 prints of Raymond Wheeler with others, including 3 prints of army map service; 6 prints of West Point 1911 Class Reunion; 2 prints of United States Army dinner, Fort Belvoir, Virginia; 2 prints of Castle Ball, depicting Virginia Wheeler; 3 prints of Raymond Wheeler with Tom Meredith on the occasion of his retirement; and 8 prints of United States Fourth Engineers' Reunion, 1948-1973 (Envelope H)
  - 19 prints depicting Raymond and Virginia Wheeler on the occasion of the presentation of an award by the Government of Laos, 1965 (Envelope I)
  - 18 prints including 12 depicting Raymond Wheeler in a social setting with his daughter, Margaret Wheeler, receiving Hoover Medal; 1 print of Raymond Wheeler and others on the occasion of the presentation of the Degree of Grand Officer by the Ambassador of Netherlands; and 5 prints depicting the award of the Wheeler Medal, 1949-1970 (Envelope J)
  - 86 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler with others involved in the Mekong River Basin Project, including Paul Bourtieres of France, P. S. Narayan Prasad, Kanwar Sain, and Virginia Wheeler, 1957-1968 (Envelope K)
  - 187 prints of Raymond Wheeler and others, including N. D. Gulhati, Alfred Katzin, Dag Hammarskjold and Kamel Hamza, involved in the United Nations Suez Canal Operations, 1956-1957 (Envelope L-Q)
    Also includes prints depicting Port Said Harbor and Lambert Brothers building, headquarters, United Nations Suez Clearance group; and the equipment used in the operations.
  - 24 prints of salvage operations in the Suez Canal, 1956-1957 (Envelope R)
  - 69 prints depicting Raymond and Virginia Wheeler with others involved in the United Nations operations in Congo; and 1 print of an upstream trip aboard the Mississippi, 1960-1972 (Envelope S)
  - 28 prints including 8 prints of Bill Arthur, his son, home at Wind River, Wyoming, and log chapel, Windriver Indian Preservation and Mirror Lake at British Columbia; 1 print of Coca Lake, Ethiopia; 8 prints of the San Francisco, California, home of Nick and Gertha Nichols; 2 prints of J. Holger Graffman and his family; 1 print of Donala Salman with his family; 1 print of Albert Schaff; 1 print of Raymond and Virginia Wheeler with Mrs. Aladin Fateen; and 7 prints of Raymond Wheeler's passport photos, 1915-1972, undated (Envelope T)
  - 30 prints including 22 depicting Raymond and Virginia Wheeler and others, including Kanwar Sain, Hart Schaaf and B. Binson during a trip to Tokyo; 1 print of Abu Simel; 1 print of Raymond Wheeler and other Directors of the Panama Canal Company; 2 prints of Raymond Wheeler and others at the site of Fondulac Dam, Peoria, Illinois; and 4 laminated prints of heavy machinery parts produced by Flexi-Versal Corporation, 1967, undated (Envelope U)
  - 12 prints including 3 prints of Mica Dam and Duncan Lake Storage Development, Columbia River Project, British Columbia; 5 prints of Raymond Wheeler with others, including Jawaharlal Nehru, Prime Minister of India, during Raymond Wheeler's visit to India; and 4 prints of his trip to Pakistan on discussions about the Indus River Project, 1950-1955, 1962-1967 (Envelope V)
  - 25 prints including 11 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler and others at Naknex, Alaska, including 1 print of Mount McKinley, and 4 prints of airstrip, float planes, and recreation camp at Naknex, landing mat at Cape Barrow; 11 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler's visit to Brazil; 1 print depicting Raymond Wheeler and others at his retirement dinner at the World Bank; 1 print of Raymond Wheeler at his desk at the World Bank; and 1 print of a desk presented to him on behalf of the World Bank and the International Finance Corporation, 1948-1949, 1964 (Envelope mW)
  - 63 prints depicting Raymond Wheeler with other unidentified individuals, undated (Envelope X-Y)
  - 39 print negatives, undated (Envelope Z)
  - 3 albums of Suez Canal operations depicting Raymond Wheeler and others involved in the project and the equipment used, circa 1957 (Album fAA-fBB)
  - 1 album depicting Raymond and Virginia Wheeler during their visit to Tarbela Dam, West Pakistan; one album depicting Raymond and Virginia Wheeler and others during their visit to West Pakistan; one album of other individuals, including Sidney Dean, Lou Heinrichs, Chris Johnson and Carl Jones, on the occasion of the Fourth Engineers' Association reunion in Oakland, California, 1961-1963, 1969 (Album fCC)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1951-1970 (Box 52)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled, unclassified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2015 May release of records, 1951-1969 (Box-folder 52: 1-5)